- [Instructor] Basic Analysis.
Value_counts, value_counts is one of
the most useful methods in pandas.
It returns a series object,
counting all the unique values.
There are two things in particular
to be aware of value_counts.
As this is returning a
count of the unique values,
the first value is the most
frequently occurring element.
The second, the second most
frequently occurring element and so on.
This order can be reversed by just setting
the ascending flag to True.
Dropna, one of the parameters
within the value_counts
is True by default and you will not get
a count of the na values.
The na values remember are
the missing data values.
If your data set has a
significant number of na values,
this can be misleading and
you can turn this feature off
by setting dropna to False.
Let's now head over now
to our Jupyter notebook,
to look at value_counts.
As we've done previously,
let's import pandas as pd
and read the CSV file into our data frame.
Everything seems to be in order
so let's head over to value_counts.
Now remember that value_counts gives you
the unique values for that series.
So if I wanted to know how
many medals were presented
each time the Olympics
were held, I can type,
oo for the data frame, Edition, value,
and I can tab to look at the
options, select value_counts,
and value_counts sorts
the values by the Olympics
where the most medals were presented
to the ones with the least
medals were presented.
So here, the most medals were
presented in the 2008 games
and for whatever reason, there
were more medals presented
in the 2000 game versus the 2004 games.
It's something that we might
want to look into a bit more.
Or let's say if I was
interested to know over the
history of the Olympics, so
that's from 1896 to 2008,
how many medals were presented to men,
and how many medals
were presented to women,
I get that information
from the Gender field,
so I would type, oo for the data frame,
the series is Gender, value_counts,
and I can see that there were
21,721 medals presented to men
over the history of the
Olympics and 7,495 to the women.
We might want to sort by
ascending order instead.
So all I need to do is to change
the ascending flag here to True,
and we can see that this has
swapped those values across.
By default, you will not get
a count of the na values.
Remember those are the
missing data values.
If your data set has a
significant number of na values,
this can be misleading.
So we will not see any
difference in our data set
as we don't have any missing data.
So if I hit shift and tab, dropna,
I need to just change dropna to False,
and there will be no
difference in what we see.
In the next video, we
will look at sort_values.