- [Instructor] Sort_values()
sorts the values in a series.
As axis is equal to zero, you
are sorting along the column
and in ascending order by default.
So if you visualize a series
as being a single column,
you are sorting the
contents of that column
in ascending order.
By default, the NaNs, or missing data,
are put right at the end.
Sort_values(), when used in
conjunction with a DataFrame,
is particularly useful as
you can sort multiple series
in ascending and descending order.
Let's head over to the Jupyter
Notebook for some examples.
Let's sort by the athletes' names.
So OO is the name of the DataFrame,
Athlete gives us the details
of the athlete's name,
and sort_values().
So this provides us the list
of all of the athletes' names
sorted by the name of the athlete.
Now if we look at the options
available within sort values,
hitting Shift + Tab provides
one of the arguments,
inplace equals false.
The inplace argument is
one we will see often.
And by default, inplace is equal to false,
which means a new series will be returned.
If we want to capture those changes,
we will need to assign it to a new series.
So I'm going to create
a new series called ATH,
and the sorted list of athlete names
will be in the series ATH.
The sort_values() is particularly useful
when used with DataFrames.
So let's sort by the
edition of the Olympics,
and the athletes' names.
So OO is the name of our DataFrame,
sort_values(), and let's say, by,
and because we're going to
be using multiple series,
we can enter them as a list.
So we sort by Edition,
and Athlete.
So before you try this
out on your notebook,
what do you expect to see?
We will be sorting by edition and names,
so the first couple of
rules will correspond
to the first edition of the Olympics,
and the first couple of
rules will have Edition 1896,
with athletes' names beginning
at the start of the alphabet.
The last couple of rules will be from
the latest data that we have,
so that's the 2008 Olympics,
with athlete's names towards
the end of the alphabet.
So let's see if the alphabet
is what we expected.
Because we have data for the 1896
as being our first Olympic,
the first couple of rules
correspond to the 1896 Olympics.
And as we can see towards
the end of our DataFrame,
the last couple of the rows
correspond to the 2008 Olympics,
which is the last Olympics
that we have data for.
Now, within each edition of the Olympics,
the athletes' names are sorted
all the way from A, B,
and C to X, Y, and Z.
And that corresponds to the 1896 Olympics,
and all the way to the 2008 Olympics.
So not surprisingly, in the 2008 Olympics,
towards the end of our DataFrame,
we have athletes with names
such as Zubari and Zueva.
And so looking at that one line of code,
we're sorting by edition first,
and then the athletes'
names, and so each section
of the edition will be sorted by athlete
for each Olympic Edition.
In the next video, we will
look at Boolean indexing.