- Boolean indexing.
Boolean vectors or conditions
can be used to filter data.
Based on a condition, pass
series of true and false values
to a series or data frame to
select and display the rules
where the series has true values.
Instead of using and, or, or not,
as with most programming languages,
you can use the following symbols instead.
Remember that if you have
more than one condition,
or Boolean vector, this must be grouped
in brackets or parentheses.
This is to ensure that
the order of operations
is carried out correctly.
Let's head over to the Jupyter notebook
to look at a couple of examples.
Let's just have an overview
of our table first.
Now let's say we wanted to select
all of the athletes who
have won a gold medal.
The condition we'd enter is oo dot Medal
and these are going to be gold medals.
So if I hit enter, I'm going to get
a whole series of trues or falses.
You can see that the first true
corresponds to this first
record, or this first true,
where this athlete has won a gold medal.
The second one, the athlete
has won a silver medal
and that's why you can
see that this is a false.
The third, the athlete
has won a bronze medal
and that's why it's a false, and so on.
Now, if we wanted to
actually evaluate this
and determine which athletes
have won gold medals,
we enter this within
square brackets as so.
And we can see that we've
now got a data frame
where all the athletes
have won a gold medal.
And we can check this by looking
at that final column here,
where all the athletes
have won a gold medal.
Let's look at another example of how
we can use Boolean Indexing.
Let's use multiple conditions.
Let's say we want to
know all women athletes
who have won a gold medal.
Remember that we need to
include the conditions
in parentheses or brackets.
And we want all women athletes.
So oo, which is the
name of our data frame,
gender, equals, equals, and then women.
And when we run this cell,
we see that we've got
a data frame with all women,
and the final column here is gold.
In the next video, we will
look at string handling.