- [Instructor] String
handling generally have names
matching the equivalent
scaler built in string methods
that are available in Python.
These are available
under the str attribute.
Using the str attribute,
you have access to several
common string methods,
such as contains, startswith,
isnumeric and so on.
Let's head over to the Jupyter notebook
to have a look at a couple of examples.
Let's say we want to look
up the legendary Flo Jo,
who is the fastest woman ever.
Her time for the 100
meter sprint from 1988
is still the fastest time recorded today.
Now if you're like me, you
can't remember her full name.
We know her name is Flo Jo,
so her first name is Florence.
So I go to my data frame, Athlete,
and I now use the new string
attribute str.contains,
and I search for Florence.
If I want to see where this is true,
so I want to see the
rows where this is true,
I enter this in square brackets,
and I can see a couple of Florences.
So, Florence Syers and so on.
Clearly the one that we're
looking for is Flo Jo
from the USA who ran the 100
meters and 200 meters in 1988.
So her full name is
Florence Griffith Joyner.
That's the end of our basic analysis.
In the next section,
we will look at a Jupyter notebook
and look at some basic data
analysis worked examples.