- [Instructor] I've got
a couple of fun problems
to work through.
We're going to practice
using some of the tools
that we've been learning
such as head, value
counts and sort values.
Why don't you have a go
at the questions first.
Once you are done,
I'll show you in the next video
how I went about answering them
but remember there's
often more than one way
to do this in Pandas.
These questions should
take you between five
and 10 minutes,
so let's have a quick
look at the questions.
In which events did
Jesse Owens win a medal?
Which country has won the
most men's gold medals
in singles badminton over the years?
Sort the results alphabetically
by the players' names.
Which three countries
have won the most medals
in recent years,
that's from 1984 to 2008?
And finally, display the
male gold medal winners
of the 100-meters track
and field sprint event
over the years.
List the results starting
with the most recent first
and show the Olympic city, edition,
athlete and the country they represent.
In the next video I'll show you
how I went about
answering these questions.