- [Instructor] Right,
now let's work through
these solutions together.
So the first thing we want
to do is import Pandas as pd,
and let's have an
overview of our data set.
First question is, in which events
did Jesse Owens win a medal?
Now, the first thing
to be aware of is that
in the Athletes field,
the names are such that
it's first the surname,
which is in capitals,
and then the first name.
So we need to be aware of that
when querying our data frame.
In which events did
Jesse Owens win a medal?
So if we look at our data frame,
we can see that the athlete names are such
that the surname is first in capitals
and then the first name.
So we need to be aware of that
when querying our data frame.
So I can enter OO dot
athlete equals, and then,
because his surname is
Owens, Owens, Jesse,
and if I hit Enter here, I'm going to get
a whole load of trues and falses.
So I encapsulate that in square brackets.
And I can see that these are the rows
corresponding to Jesse Owens.
If I assign the data frame
JO for Jesse Owens to that,
and then if I want to just get the events
that he was involved in and nothing else,
I could do JO dot events dot value counts,
and this will give me all of the events
that Jesse Owens took part in.
Let's go on to the next question.
Which country has won the
most men's gold medals
in singles badminton over the years?
Sort the results alphabetically
by the player's names.
So the first thing to notice here
is that we've got multiple conditions,
and each of those conditions
needs to be in brackets.
So OO medal type, which is gold.
And OO dot gender, which is men.
And OO dot sport, which is badminton.
Now, I'm not sure whether it's the sport
or the event which is badminton,
so I can just do a quick check here.
I do OO dot sport dot value counts,
and see whether that comes
under Event or Sport.
And I can see here that
badminton is, in fact,
listed under Sport, so that query is fine.
And if I encapsulate that
in square brackets, as such,
and call that data frame
gold, badminton, and men,
so GBM, and we see we've got the results
for countries that have won gold medals
in badminton over the years.
So that's Korea, Indonesia, Denmark,
Indonesia, China, Korea, and so on.
Now, if I want to sort
the results alphabetically
by the player's names, I
can chain those requests
onto the GBM.
So GBM dot sort values, and this is where
I'm sorting by the data
frame, so I say by,
athlete, and you can see that the results
are now sorted by the
surname of the athletes.
Onto the next question.
Which three countries
have won the most medals
in recent years?
So clearly we have the
conditional operator here,
and we need to use OO dot edition,
which is the years of the Olympics,
and I want all of the years
which are greater than
or equal to 1984, and
since the last values
in our data set is 2008, I
don't need to specifically
specify the years that are
less than or equal to 2008.
And so if I do that, and I
call that data frame recent,
and I hit Enter, these
are all of the countries
that have won medals in recent years.
Now, if I want the three countries
that have won the most medals,
I'm going to have to use value count.
So I do REC, NOC for the
countries, value counts,
and that's going to sort the
number of medals received
by those countries from 1984 onwards.
And you can see that USA has won the most,
then Australia, Germany,
and China, and so on.
Now, if I want to specify the top three,
I can use head, use the parameter three,
and that gives me the results that I need.
Let's move on to the next question.
Display the male gold medal
winners for the 100 meters
track and field sprint
event over the years.
List the results starting
with the most recent.
Show the Olympic city, edition, athlete,
and the country they represent.
So again, multiple conditions here.
So gold, male, and let's say 100 meters.
So remember that we need to
include all of those conditions
in brackets, so gender, men.
And medal, gold.
And the event, well, I'm not sure what
the event title is, so
let me have a quick look
at the value counts for that.
So event dot value counts,
and I will be able to get
the format of those events.
And I can see that the
events have this format
of four times 100 meters and so on.
So I can use OO event and then 100 meters,
and that will give me
the result that I want.
So let's have a look and see whether
this gives me what I want.
And you can see, then, that
yes, it is the 100 meters
that the men have won, and
they've all received gold medals.
So let's list the results starting with
the most recent first.
So we sort values by edition,
and critically, we need to
change that ascending flag.
So ascending is equal to false.
And we can see now that we've
got the 100 meters winner,
Usain Bolt, for 2008.
The 100 meters winner in
2004, which is Justin Gatlin.
Maurice Greene in 2000, and so on, right?
But this data frame has
several more columns
than has been requested in the question.
So for example, we have
things like the event,
the event gender, and so on,
which has not been requested.
So in order to specify
these additional series,
we can include them as a list.
So we say the Olympic
city, which is just city.
The edition.
The athlete name.
And the country name, which is NOC.
And here we have that.
So we can see that Usain
Bolt won the 100 meters gold
in the 2008 event, and he's from Jamaica.
Justin Gatlin, from the
US, won the 100 meters gold
in 2004, and so on.
And you can see that using a combination
of sort values and
value counts can help us
answer some fairly interesting
questions about our data.