- [Instructor] Data Visualizations.
Using the Olympic data set
we have used so far in this course,
let's say you wanted to present a summary
of the total medals won
by participating countries
in the 2008 Beijing Olympics.
Which of these two do you find
more intuitive and readable?
I hope you'll agree with me
that the heatmap is far
more intuitive and helpful.
Let's look to see how we can create these
in our Jupiter Notebook.
Because we're going to be using Seaborn,
let's import Seaborn
as sns.
What we want here are all the medals
won in the 2008 Olympics.
So, oo.Edition
equals 2008.
Let's store that in the
data frame Last Olympics.
Now we have in our data frame LO,
all of the medals won by the athletes
in the 2008 Beijing Olympics.
I want to group by the
countries, which is the NOC,
and the medals won.
I do a size off of that.
We can see that we've
got a group by object
sorted alphabetically by
the different countries
and the medals won.
Let's unstack this
with medal,
and we'll fill value
with zero.
Let's look at the result of that.
We've got a couple of
challenges with our data frame.
Firstly, it doesn't seem to be sorted
in order of the number of medals.
Secondly, we've got the column headings
as bronze, gold, and silver.
So let's modify that.
I'm going to call this group by object g,
and I'm going to sort values by
gold,
silver,
and bronze;
which is a list.
Let's include that as a list
of gold, silver, and bronze.
Remember that we want
this in descending order.
I then view that.
I've got the medals in descending
order for the countries.
The only challenge I still have
is that the column headings
are still bronze, gold, and silver.
We can easily modify that
by saying we want that
in the sequence gold, silver, bronze.
Let's store that in the data frame g.
So we have the table that
we want with the countries
sorted by the number of gold,
silver, and bronze medals
that they won in the 2008 Olympics.
Let's plot this using a heat map.
Sns for Seaborn,
heatmap,
and as input we provide the data frame.
We've got a couple of
challenges with this figure.
Firstly, the gold, silver and
bronze is across the x axes,
with the countries along the y axes.
If we swap those around,
then perhaps the country
names will be more readable.
Secondly, we need to
increase this figure size.
Let's do a transpose of the data frame.
Let's have a look at the data frame.
Now we have the different countries
as columns across the top,
and we've got each row
corresponding to the number
of gold, silver, and bronze medals.
We seem to be in a better position now,
so let's change the figure size.
Plot figure,
figure size.
Let's make this 16 inches by five inches.
We've got the heatmap g.
Here you see we've got the
gold, silver, and bronze medals
across the y axes,
and we've got the different
countries across the x axes.
This makes for very intuitive reading.
There are a couple of insights
that we can gain from this straight away.
We can see that the
USA has a higher number
of gold and silver versus bronze medals.
We can see that China
has a higher proportion of gold medals.
Australia has significantly
more bronze than gold or silver medals.
Similarly, we can see
that both Spain and Cuba
have the highest proportion of medals
in the silver category.
There seems to have been a
very closely fought battle
for the third position with
Russia, Germany, South Korea,
and The Netherlands.
As you can see, the Seaborn heatmaps
provide some very intuitive plots.
Next, we will look at
creating our own color maps.