- [Instructor] Creating your own colormap.
Which of these two figures
provides a more effective plot?
This one versus this one.
You might recognize the plot on the left
as being the solution from chapter eight.
With colormaps we can
create our own colors.
Let's see how we this
in our Jupyter notebook.
I'm going to copy the
solution from chapter eight
and let's see if we can
visualize this more effectively.
I'm going to talk you through
the solution very quickly
to remind you what we did.
And then we look to see how we can
plot this more effectively.
I'm going to use comments
or this hash symbol
to break this solution
into multiple steps.
So the question was,
"Plot the five athletes
"who have won the most gold medals
"over the history of the Olympics.
"When there is a tie, consider
the number of silver medals
and then bronze medals."
So firstly we're going to
group by the athlete medals.
And we can see that we've
grouped by the athlete
and the type of medal that they've won.
We then unstack that to get a table
with different columns of
gold, silver, and bronze.
We can then use sort
values to order the medals
in descending order, sorting
by gold, silver, and bronze.
And then head allows us
to see the top five values
and we can then plot that.
We will need to use
Matplotlib's listed colormap
to create our own colormap.
This allows us to make a
colormap from a list of colors.
So I'm going to import the
listed colormap function.
So from matplotlib dot
colors import ListedColormap.
Let's run that.
Seaborn's color palette
is one of the most important functions
for working with the
discrete color palettes.
Color palette provides an interface
to most of the colors you
can generate in Seaborn.
Let's say you wanted to see the
current default color cycle.
We could type sns for
Seaborn and color_palette.
Now this isn't particularly helpful.
So if we plot the values in
a color palette using palplot
we get sns dot palplot.
I copy that code from above and we can see
that these are the current
default color cycles.
Now what I've done is I've gone online
to find the hexadecimal codes
for gold, silver, and bronze
and created a list with these values.
So I'm going to create the
list for my color palette
using the variable gsb
for gold, silver, bronze.
And then I'm going to
use Seaborn's palplot
to view this palette.
And I provide as an argument gsb.
So what I need to do is to grab the code
that I generated earlier
and apply my new colormap to this code.
Just to make this a
little bit more readable,
I'm going to assign g to the head
and I'm going to add
that to the next line.
The only change I need to make
is to add my newly created colormap.
Colormap equals my underscore gsb.
And you can see that we have a
far more effective plot here.
So as you can see,
customizing your colormaps
can be very effective and
useful for your projects.
I highly recommend you try them out.
In the next video we will look at our
final challenge problem.