- [Instructor] Groupby is one
of the most important
functionalities available in Pandas.
Groupby does three things.
It splits a DataFrame into groups
based on some criteria,
it applies a function to
each group independently
and it combines the
results into a DataFrame.
Now, many people when they first learn
how to use the Groupby function,
don't know what to do
with the Groupby object.
Creating the Groupby object only verifies
that you've passed a valid mapping.
The Groupby object isn't a DataFrame
but rather a group of DataFrames
in a dict-like structure.
On the next slide, we have
a useful visualization
that helps us show what
the Groupby function does.
So, Groupby splits the
DataFrame into groups.
Each of these groups
remember is a DataFrame,
it applies a function for each group
and then finally it combines
the results into a DataFrame.
Let's head over to the Jupyter Notebook
to look at a couple of examples.
So, let's import Pandas as PD.
We read the Olympic CSV file
into our DataFrame called 00
and now let's Groupby by the edition,
so we use the DataFrame 00,
Groupby and we're grouping by edition
and as you can see this
returns a Groupby object.
Now, let's determine what
type this Groupby object is,
so I'm just going to copy this
and I say type
and we can see that the Groupby object
is of type DataFrameGroupby.
Now you can actually put this into a list
to see how the things are grouped
when grouping by objects,
so let's use the list command
and we can see that the Groupby object
is first the edition
and then all of the rows
corresponding to that edition
and then if we scroll further down,
we'll find that it's the next year,
1900 and then all of the
rows corresponding to 1900.
In the next video we
will look at iterating
through a group.