- [Narrator] We can
iterate through groups.
As we mentioned earlier,
each of these groups are data frames.
What we can do here,
is to print out the key
and then print out the rows
corresponding to that key.
As an example, on the olympics
dataset we are working on,
if we group by each olympic here,
then the key would be the
olympic edition or year,
and the group portion would be
all of the rows corresponding
to that edition.
Then Groupby prints the
next olympic edition,
followed by all of the rows
corresponding to that edition.
Let's take a look in our Jupyter notebook.
So what we want to do here is to look
through the Groupby object,
for group key
group value in,
and then a Groupby object
which is Edition in this case,
we are grouping by edition.
This is just a very simple Python script.
I want to print the group key
and I want to print the group value.
And I change that to value,
and the group value
and let's run this.
And basically what we see here
is what we saw in the
list command earlier,
so this is the key, which is the edition,
or the year of that olympics, and then
all of the rows
corresponding to that year,
the next one will be for the 1900,
and all of the rows
corresponding to that year.
So let's confirm what type
each of these groups are.
So the rows corresponding to each year.
So remember, that type has
the variable group value
so I type group value
and not surprisingly,
this is a data frame.
In the next video, we will
look at Groupby computations.