- [Instructor] There are several functions
you can perform on a groupby object.
The size function was gives
you a count of each group
is particularly helpful.
But there are several others.
Here's a helpful real world tip.
Many times you might want to
use the aggregation function.
The aggregation function, AGG,
allows multiple statistics
to be calculated per group
in one calculation.
Instructions for aggregation are provided
in the form of a python
dictionary or a list.
And the dictionary keys
are where you specify
which series or columns
in your data frame you want
to perform the operations
and the actual dictionary values
specify the function to run.
You can also pass custom functions
to the list of aggregated calculations
and each will be passed the values
from the column in your grouped data.
Groupby is a very useful Pandas function
and it's worth your time
making sure you understand how to use it.
Let's head over to the Jupyter Notebook
to look at a couple of examples.
As we mentioned earlier,
one of the useful functions
to use with group by is the size function.
So oo.groupby, and if
we group by the edition,
we can pass this to the size function
which gives us the count of that group.
And so here we can see
that there were 151 medals
distributed in 1896.
And there were 2,042 medals
distributed in the 2008 Olympics.
The aggregate function allows
for multiple statistics
to be calculated per
group in one calculation.
Now because most of the
series that we are working on
in our Olympics data
set are string objects
we won't get many useful insights.
Let's group by the edition,
the country represented, and the medals.
Oo.groupby, and we're
grouping by the edition,
the country, and the medals.
And using the aggregate function,
we can perform several
statistical functions
so let's use min, max,
and count as an example.
And as we discussed earlier,
since most of the columns are strings,
we do not get any useful output
as a result of the min, max, and count.
All min and max are doing
are sorting the values in that
series in alphabetical order.
We could try and simplify this.
By just using the count function instead.
And so we remove min and max.
And because this is just a single function
we don't have to use a list
so we can just use that element
here and remove the list.
And we will get the same result.
In this instance, again,
the aggregate function
isn't particularly helpful
as we just get a count
for the number of medals
across each of the different series.
What we can do instead is to
just use the size function
and we will get a cleaner output.
Let's head over to the other
use of the aggregate function,
which is the dict like structure.
Now reusing some of the code from earlier,
if we group by the edition,
the country, and the medal,
we can use the dict
structure on the edition
and we see that we get a cleaner output.
This is a dict structure
so I need to end that with a bracket.
And again, because we're
grouping by the edition,
the country, and the medal,
the min and max are the same values
because they correspond
to the same edition.
So remember that this is only because
most of the series in our
dataset is non numeric,
that we can't get any
interesting insights.
If each one was numeric,
then we would get very
rich statistical insights
for each column where we could specify
the min, the max, the
average, the count, and so on.
In the real world, aggregate
is a very helpful function.
Since the edition series in our dataset
is the only numeric column,
let's see if we can get
any interesting insights
on an athlete such as Carl Lewis,
who took part in multiple Olympic games.
So let's look for Carl Lewis.
So Lewis, Carl.
And group by athlete.
This time we'll aggregate
on the edition field
as this is the only
numeric field that we have,
so edition, min, max, and count.
Any guesses for what this does?
Well this is going to
provide the first Olympics
that he won a medal in, which was in 1984.
Remember that we don't know
if he took part in any earlier Olympics,
this dataset is only for
Olympic medal winners.
We also have the last
Olympics that he took part in
which is in 1996,
and we see that he's
won 10 medals in total.
So I recommend that you
use the aggregate function,
especially when you have a dataset
that has several series
which are numerical values.
The group by is incredibly helpful
and I recommend that you take the time
to understand how it works.
In the next video, we will
look at a group by challenge.