- [Instructor] So, let's import Pandas
and read the CSV file
into our DataFrame 00.
So, using Groupby,
plot the total number of medal awarded
at each of the Olympic
Games throughout history.
So, this is the same question
that we looked at in
the indexing challenge
and here's another way to get
the same result using Groupby.
So, 00's my DataFrame.
I'm going to Groupby the edition
and I'm going to use the size object
to determine the count for each group
and let's see what we get here.
So, unlike in indexing,
we see that Groupby sorts
the index by default
and so, we can see it's 1896 to 1900
and so on and all of the years here
are sorted by the Olympic year,
so we don't have to use these sort index
like we had to in the indexing example.
So, all I need to do now
is to just plot this line
and we end up with exactly the same result
as we did in the indexing challenge.
Onto the next question.
Create a list showing the
total number of medals,
one for each country
over the history of the Olympics.
For each country, include the year
of the first and the most
recent Olympic medal wins.
So, I suggest we start by
just grouping by the country,
so Groupby NOC
and let's use the basic
aggregate function first.
So, we need the count
and note that because
it's asking for the first
and the most recent medal win,
what we want to use
is the min and the max information
that is available in the
Olympics edition field.
So, count, min and max.
Now again we see that series such as city,
the sport and the discipline
do not provide us with
much useful information.
However, when we look
at the edition series,
we see that for each country
we have the number of medals won,
when the first medal was won
which was the min and when
the last medal was won,
so for example, Afghanistan
seems to have won
its first medal in the 2008 Olympics.
If we scroll down,
we can see that the USA
won its first medal in 1896,
it's most recent medal in 2008
and the USA has won 4,335 medals
over the history of the Olympics.
Given that the edition field
was the most useful to us,
let's use aggregate's dict structure
to only get information
on the edition field,
so I use Python's dict structure here,
edition,
and so, that's the key,
these are the values
and this is our Python dict structure
and we can see here that we've got a list
of all of the countries,
the total number of
medals that the countries
have won over the history of the Olympics
and when the country won
its first Olympic medal
and its most recent Olympic medal.
As you can see, the Groupby function
is incredibly useful in Pandas.
In the next video we will
look at stack and unstack.