- [Jonathan] Right, so
the spirit of the Olympics
is all about finishing the race.
So, well done.
You've made it to the end of this course.
Now one of my favorite quotes
is from the Olympian Eric Liddell.
He says, "I believe God
made me for a purpose,
"but he also made me fast!
"And when I run I feel his pleasure."
So if data science is what excites you,
then I hope I've helped you get better.
You have now got several more
Pandas tools and resources
to turn to when analyzing
your next data set.
So what next?
Here are a couple of ideas.
So you could use our Olympics data set
to answer some of the following trivia
Olympics questions listed here.
Alternatively, you can add data
from the 2012 Olympics
onwards from other sources
to the data set we've used and find out
what new insights you can find.
I hope you've enjoyed this course
as much as I did putting it together.
If you'd like to get in touch,
write me at theolympicsguy@gmail.com.
Enjoy, and Soli Deo Gloria.