- [Jonathan] Welcome.
I'm Jonathan Fernandes
and I'm really excited
about this course as it
includes two things I enjoy,
Python's Pandas and the Olympics.
So Pandas is an open source
library that provides
easy to use data analysis
tools for the Python
programming language.
So the purpose of this
course is to be hands on
and very practical.
So each section builds the
knowledge that you would
have picked up in earlier
parts of the course.
So you learn how to
manipulate and query data
more effectively and
the tools that you learn
in this course will help you
become a better data scientist.
So we'll cover topics such
as Series and DataFrames,
plotting, indexing,
Groupby, stack and unstack,
and some data visualizations.
Remember, if you want to get
the most out of this course,
work through the challenge exercises.
The data set we'll be
using are the medal winners
for the Summer Olympics from 1896 to 2008,
and I can't wait to get started.
See you at the Olympics.