- [Narrator] A dataframe is
like a two dimensional area.
You can think of a dataframe
as being like a table or a
spreadsheet with rows and columns.
You can see from our Olympics
data set that the dataframe
is made up of several
columns such as the city,
the addition, and sport.
And each entry, or row,
corresponds to a medal
that an athlete has won.
This is all there is to a dataframe.
Let's head over to the Jupiter notebook
to understand a little
bit more about dataframes.
The first thing we'll need
to do in our notebook,
is to import pandas.
Inport pandas as pd.
Now we will make more sense
of these next few lines in the
read csv video, so don't
worry to much about them.
Basically what we are doing here is
we are reading the csv file
into a dataframe called oo,
so let's run that.
In order to view the dataframe,
we enter the dataframes name which is oo
and run that cell.
The Jupiter notebook will
display the first 30 rows
and the last 30 rows.
And we can see that in this dataframe,
we have 29,216 rows.
In the next video, we will
look at panda's series.