- [Instructor] A Series
is a one-dimensional
array of indexed data.
One of the huge benefits of Pandas
is that it supports both integer
and label-based indexing,
and provides a host of methods
for performing operations
involving the index.
The first column is known as an index.
And, each of the other columns
corresponds to a Series.
The first Series is called City,
where the Olympics were held.
The second Series is called the Edition,
and this is the year the
Olympics were held, and so on.
Now, remember that each of
the rows is also a Series,
and this can be identified
by this index number.
So, how do you access the Series?
Well, there are two ways
of going about this.
You can access them
using a square bracket,
using either a single quote
or a double quote, notation.
So, for example, you
provide the dataframe name,
and then the series name,
in either single quotes, or double quotes,
or you can use the dot notation.
The square bracket notation
for accessing a Series, will always work.
The dot notation can be a shortcut,
but it will not work if there's
a space in the Series name.
So, if you want to use the dot notation,
you need to make certain that
each of the column names
does not have a space.
You can also access multiple series,
and you can do that by including
the series name in a list.
We will look at other
ways to access portions
of the dataset in later videos.
Now, Series and dataframes are
an essential part of Pandas,
and you want to get comfortable
with working with them.
There are sometimes
different methods available
to dataframes and Series,
and if you're not sure
if you're working with a Series object,
or a dataframe object,
the type function can be a great help.
In this instance, we can
see that the dataframe
is of type pandas, core, dataframe.
In the same way, if we include
a dataframe in a Series name,
then the type is of type Series.
Notice that if we use a couple of Series,
then the type of that
object is a dataframe.
Let's head over to the Jupiter Notebook,
for a couple of examples.
So, remember that oo is my dataframe,
and if I scroll up here,
I can see that these were
the names of my Series.
If I want to access the Series,
the first way we mentioned was
the square bracket notation,
so I can specify the dataframe,
and the name of the Series.
So, for example City,
which is the City that
the Olympics was held in.
And, here I get a Series,
which is just the City
column for that dataframe.
If I want to get a list of the Athletes,
I can type Athlete, and here
I will only get the column
with all of the Athlete names.
The other way of accessing
the Athlete information
is to use the dot notation,
which is oo.Athlete, and shift
and enter to run that cell.
And you can see, I get exactly
the same output, as earlier.
Now, remember that I can
only use the dot notation
when there are no spaces
in the column name.
If I want to access a couple of columns,
or a couple of Series, I can do oo,
and include the Series names in a list.
So, I can enter the City, the Edition,
and the Athlete name, and run that cell.
Now, it's very important
that you understand
which object you're working with.
So, we know that oo is the dataframe, but
let's confirm that by
looking at the type command.
We know that the oo.City is a Series,
and we can confirm that using type.
What might have not
been so obvious is that
if we use a couple of Series,
such as City, Edition, and Athlete,
so if I just copy that cell,
this type is also a dataframe.
In the next video, we will look at
a couple of challenge exercises.