- [Instructor] So, remember
to run the first couple
of lines, so we want
to import Pandas as PD,
so I run that by hitting shift and enter.
I want to load the CSV file
into my DataFrame called 00
and so, the first question is list
our Olympics DataFrame.
Now, since our DataFrame is called 00,
all we need to do type 00
and run that cell
and we can see that we've got
the entire DataFrame here.
The next question is to
list only the NOC column
using both the square bracket notation
and the dot notation.
So, 00 is my DataFrame
and the NOC column is NOC in all capitals
and I can run that and you can see
that this is displayed in
the way that we expect.
So, the first country's Hungary and so on.
And if I want to do the same thing
but with the dot notation,
I type 00 which is my DataFrame
and then the series name which is NOC.
And I get exactly the same
results as I did above.
Now, the final question is to determine
what type this object is,
so all we need to do is
call the type function,
so type, parentheses 00.NOC
and close parentheses and run that
and we can see that this a series object.
And the final question
is to list the edition,
the city, the athlete name
and the medal columns.
So, if you're not sure what
those column names look like,
you can always scroll up to the top
and you've got the information there.
So, I can do that by including them
in a Python list,
so I've got edition,
the city,
the athlete's name which
is given by just the column
and the medal.
And if I run this,
I get those four columns listed.
Now, it's really important
that you understand
that what Python has done here
is to generate a new DataFrame
and this new DataFrame has
these different columns.
So, what kind of object is this?
Well, I've given the answer away
in my previous comment,
it's type and it's a DataFrame object.
In the next video we will look
at data input and validation.