- [Teacher] Basic plotting, in this video
we will look at basic plotting.
Matplotlib tries to make
easy things easy and
hard things possible,
that's what it says on the website.
You can generate plots,
histograms, bar charts,
error charts with just
a few lines of code.
For simple plotting, the pyplot module
provides a MATLAB-like interface.
The line "import matplotlib.pyplot"
allows you to use the
matplotlib.pyplot module
using the abbreviation plt.
One of the features of the IPython kernel
is the ability to display plots
that are the output of running code cells.
The IPython kernel works seamlessly
with the Matplotlib Plotting Library
to provide this functionality.
To set this up,
you must execute that second line,
matplotlib inline
and that's what's known
as a merger command.
With the Matplotlib inline backend,
the output of the plotting
commands is displayed inline,
within the Jupiter Notebook,
directly below the code
cell that produced it.
The resulting plots
will then also be stored
in the notebook document.
Now, any basic Matplotlib tutorial
will reference instantiating
axes or figure objects.
When dealing with more complicated plots,
where you require more
control over the plots,
you will want to
explicitly define the axes
and or the figure objects
that you will be using.
In this course, we are primarily dealing
with the shorter scripts.
And the pyplot method
of Matplotlib is ideal.
In the next video,
we will look at the
different kinds of plots.