- [Narrator] Types of plot.
The plot command displays the graph
and there are a couple of options.
By default, the graph is a line plot,
but you can also specify that you want
to use another type of graph such as
a barh graph or a pie chart.
You need to use the kind equals parameter
to specify what type of plot you require.
Half of the skill is
in trying to determine
which graph would be the
best to represent the data.
So, you'd normally use a line graph
when you're trying to track changes
of a short or a long period of time.
When smaller changers exist, line graphs
are better to use than, say, a bar graph
and line graphs can also
be used to compare changes
of the same period of time
for more than one group.
A bar graph or a horizontal bar graph
have the same use cases.
Bar graphs are used to compare things
between different groups or
to track changes over time.
However, when trying to
measure change over time,
bar graphs are best when
the changes are large.
This is the horizontal bar graph
and it's almost identical to a bar graph,
but it has its axes flipped over.
Pie charts are best to use
when you're trying to
compare parts of a whole.
They do not show changes over time.
Let's turn to the Jupiter
notebook for some examples.
Alright, so let's import pandas as pd,
read-in our data set into the data frame
and now we need to import
the matplotlib library.
import matplotlib.pyplot as plt
and this is the magic amount;
matplotlib inline and this will alow us
to view the graphs and
the plots in our notebook.
So, the question is:
What were the different
sports in the first Olympics?
Plot them using different graphs.
Now, from an earlier section, we know
that if we want to determine the sports
in the first Olympics, we need to first
search by the addition and so,
fo which is the first Olympics
is the data frame that stores that data.
I can then plot this using the data frame
fo.sport.value_counts and
this gives us the different
sports that were available
in the first Olympics.
I can then chain the plot command to this
and remember, by default,
we will get a line plot.
To confirm that, I'm going to do
kind equals line and we get the same plot.
If I want to suppress
this matplotlib.axes here,
I can add a semicolon to the end
of that line and run the cell again.
Moving onto a bar plot, given
that we are going to be using
the same line, I'm just going
to copy this line of code
and the only change we need to make
is that we need to specify
that the plot is a bar plot
and I can suppress that extra line there
and you can see that the bar plot
is a far more useful plot in
this instance than a line plot,
because it had overlapping
labels in the axes.
Similarly, we can use the horizontal plot
and all we need to do is kind equals barh
for the horizontal plot and we get
the same information as you would
for a bar plot except
the axes are swapped over
and finally, we can
plot using a pie chart.
So, using exactly the same
line of code; plot(kind=pie);
remember that you wouldn't use
all of the different plots for you data.
In this instance, the
bar, the horizontal bar
and the pie charts were the most
effective in representing this data.
In this instance, I wouldn't
use the line graphs.
In the next video, we
will look at color plots.