- [Instructor] Plot colors.
You have a couple of options
with regards to plot colors,
and you need to just specify
the name of the color
using the color parameter.
In addition to this, you can include
the type of plot that
you want and the color.
Matplotlib has several inbuilt colors,
and they are available on
the Matplotlib website.
Let's head over to the Jupyter Notebook
to look at an example.
So using the same code as earlier,
I'm going to specify that
the color needs to be plum.
And you can see that you
get the default line plot
in plum color.
Alternatively, I could
specify that I want a
bar graph,
and I want it in maroon.
In the next video, we will
look at how we can manipulate
the figure size in Matplotlib.