- [Instructor] Colormaps are
included with Matplotlib.
The idea behind choosing a cool colormap,
is to find a good
representation of your data.
It there an intuitive
color scheme for the data?
For example gold, silver,
and bronze for medal winners.
Blue for male, pink for female?
There are three classes of colormaps.
The sequential, the diverging,
and the qualitative.
The sequential should be used
for representing information
that has ordering.
There is a change in lightness,
often over a single hue.
Diverging is to be used when
the information being plotted
deviates around a middle value.
Here there are often two
different colors being used.
And finally, the qualitative
class is used to represent
information which does not have any
ordering or relationship,
and is often miscellaneous colors.
Let's head over to the Jupiter notebook
to look at a couple of examples.
Let's use the pie chart
as our first example,
so we need to specify that
the kind of plot that you want
is a pie chart,
and here we can specify that the colormap
is Pastel1 for example.
Notice that you would have
run into problems if you
tried to plot a pie chart
using the color parameter,
as this doesn't exist.
In the next video, we
will look at Seaborn.
Which provides very rich
and beautiful plots.