- [Presenter] Seaborn Basic Plotting.
Seaborn is a visualization
library based on Matplotlib.
One of the reasons to use Seaborn
is that it produces
beautiful statistical plots.
It is very important to realize
that Seaborn is a complement
and not a substitute to Matplotlib.
Now one of the advantages
again with using Seaborn
is that it works very well with pandas.
Seaborn has an excellent examples gallery
that provides plots on the website,
and if you click on any of the plots,
it provides the code
to generate that plot.
Seaborn, as with Matplotlib,
has methods for bar plots,
histograms and pie charts.
Let's take a look at an example
of one of the methods, countplot.
Countplot has very similar
parameters to Matplotlib.
The data parameter for
countplot is where you provide
the DataFrame or the source for the data.
The hue is for the categorical variables.
A categorical variable
is one that can only take
a fixed number of values.
In the Olympics dataset,
we have a couple of examples
of categorical variables.
There are only a limited number of sports,
the gender is either male or female,
and medals are gold, silver or bronze.
The hue allows you to specify
a categorical variable
in a different color.
The order parameter
allows you to determine
the sequence of the categorical variables.
And finally, the palette parameter
allows you to specify colors
for the different levels
of the hue variable.
So when would you use
Seaborn versus Matplotlib?
If you're running a couple of scripts,
then Matplotlib with pyplot is easy to use
and great for bar charts,
pie charts and so on.
If you're looking to write short scripts
to deal with things like categorical data,
or more advanced statistical plots,
or creating other kinds
of plots such as heatmaps,
then Seaborn is going to be your choice.
Let's head over to the Jupyter
Notebook for an example.
Now because we have
already imported Matplotlib
and the pandas library
and the dataset earlier,
we don't need to do that again.
What we do need to do is to
import the Seaborn library.
So import Seaborn as sns and run that.
Now let's understand a little bit more
about the countplot method.
How many medals have
been won by men and women
in the history of the Olympics?
Well, using the sns library,
we know that we're trying to
determine the number of medals,
our data source is our DataFrame oo,
and we can see here that
the number of medals won
by men and women in the
history of the Olympics
is presented in this plot.
Now if we wanted to know the number of
gold, silver and bronze
medals won for each gender,
this is where we can use
the categorical variable.
And all we need to do here
is to add hue equals gender
and that will allow us to present
the distribution of gold,
silver and bronze medals
amongst the men and the women.
In the next video, we will
look at a plotting challenge.