- [Instructor] So I'm really excited
about chapter five's challenge.
These problems should only
take five to 10 minutes,
and I've provided a
work solution for them.
Now remember that they're
going to be multiple ways
to solve these problems,
and I've just provided my solution here.
So let's get on to the
challenge questions.
Plot the number of medals
achieved by the Chinese team,
so that's both the men and women,
in Beijing 2008 using
Matplotlib and Seaborn.
How can you use colormaps to
give the data more meaning?
Plot the number of gold, silver,
and bronze medals for each gender.
And finally, how can you
give the data more meaning?
Is there anything else you can change
to make it more intuitive?
I'll see you in the next video
where I work through these examples.