- [Instructor] Onto the
basic plotting challenge.
So, we've imported Pandas.
The next thing we're going to have to do
is to import matplotlib.
So, pyplot as plt
and we want to be able to see the plots
in our Jupyter Notebook.
We'll also want to import seaborn as sns.
Let me just run all of these cells again.
Right, onto the first question.
Plot the number of medals achieved
by the Chinese team,
that's the men and women,
in Beijing 2008 using
matplotlib and seaborn.
So, in Pandas, we want
to be able to identify
the men and women who have participated
from team China
in the Beijing Olympics
which is in 2008.
So, 00 for the DataFrame, 00.Edition
and we're looking for 2008
and remember that because we are going
to be having multiple conditions,
we need to enclose them in brackets
and we're looking for team China.
We get that information
from the series NOC,
so 00.NOC equals CHN.
Now, I'm going to assign this
to the DataFrame men and women,
so mw and let's just check
and make sure that we've got some entries
in that DataFrame.
Right, now if I want to plot this
using matplotlib,
I want the gender, so men and women,
the gender series,
value_counts and let's just view that
and then plot kind equals
bar for the bar plot.
And I've got the men and women here.
Now, using seaborn I
can use the countplot,
so sns countplot and
remember I need to specify
the dataset that I received that from,
so data equals 00,
that's from the Olympics DataFrame,
and we're plotting the gender,
so that's in quotes.
And you can see that the seaborn plot
looks nicer than the matplotlib plot.
Onto the next question.
How can you use colormaps
to give the data more meaning?
Now, knowing that we're
plotting men versus women,
let's see if we can determine
using the colormap classes
what would provide a more intuitive plot,
so for example, if we can
get the men to be in blue
and the women to be in pink or red,
that would be a far
better, more intuitive plot
than using any other random color.
Now, looking through these colormaps,
we can see for example
that coolwarm and bwr
meet those conditions
and we have blue on one end
and we've got pink or
red at the other end,
so let's use bwr as an example.
So, we can take the code
from the previous line here
and what we need to do here
is to just use a palette
and we're going to use the palette bwr.
Now, doesn't that look so much better
and more intuitive than
the plot that we had above
with the blue and the green?
Plot the number of gold, silver and bronze
for each gender.
So, if we use seaborn's countplot,
and we're looking for the
X variable to be the medal,
our DataFrame is mw
and the hue which is the
categorical variable is gender.
And we can see that we've
got the distribution
of medals for team China
across the gold, silver and bronze.
So, how can we build on the previous plot
and make the data more intuitive?
Well, let's take the one
line script from here
and remember from the
earlier part of the solution
we determined that the colormaps bwr
helped to provide an intuitive color
for men and women.
So, if we use a palette of bwr,
we have got a far more
meaningful plot here.
Now, there seems to be one problem
that we have because we've got the order
of the X axis as being
silver, bronze and gold
and we can easily change that
by determining the order of
the categorical variables,
so we specify order equals
gold, silver and bronze.
And by changing the colors
for the men and the women plot
and by changing the order
for the gold, silver and bronze medals,
we've made this a far more
intuitive and usable plot.
In the next video,
we will look at indexes.