- [Instructor] We're going
to look at two new functions
that are very helpful,
especially when used in
conjunction with group by.
The stack function allows
you to move the inner columns
to the rows for the dataframe
and the unstack function does the reverse.
The next slide has a helpful visualization
that will help you understand
what both the stack and
the unstack functions do.
The stack function helps you
to reshape the dataframe.
The table on the top left
is the original dataframe.
What I have captured here are the athletes
that's both the male and female athletes
that won medals at the
Beijing 2008 Olympics
in both the 100 meters and
the 200 meters athletic events
and which countries they represented.
Let's head over to the Jupyter Notebook
and create this table,
so let's import pandas as pd,
import our dataset into the dataframe.
Let's take a look at the athletes
that took part in the 100 meters
or the 200 meters track event,
so we want to use our dataframe
and remember that there are going to be
a couple of conditions
so we want to include all
of them in parenthesis,
so the athletes take
part in the 2008 Olympics
so oo.edition equals 2008
and we want to know which ones
took part in the 100 meters
or the 200 meters.
Right, so let's enter the
conditions for the 100 meters,
so oo.event equals 100 meters
and oo.event equals 200 meters
and let's show that in a dataframe
for men and women so mw equals that
and let's just check the
results of our dataframe.
So, we can confirm that
this is the 2008 Olympics.
Men and women taking part in
the 100 and 200 meters event
and these are the medals
that they have won.
The next thing we want to do
is to group by the country
they represent, the gender,
the discipline they are
taking part in and the event.
Let's assign this to the
letter g, the group by object,
and let's run that.
And now, in order to get the same view
as the original dataframe,
we need to unstack this so
g unstack the discipline
and the event.
Let's store this in a dataframe
and we can see that we've got
the dataframe that we want.
Don't worry too much about
the unstacking function.
We will look at it in more detail shortly.
Great, so now we have the
dataframe that's required
for us to do the stacking
and unstacking function.
Let's look at stacking first.