- [Teacher] When using the stack function,
the stack function returns
a data frame or a series.
And notice that you will never have any
any values or missing
data because by default
the drop any flag is equal to true.
The inner levels of a
stack function are sorted.
So when we do a stack we are returning a
data frame or series with a
new innermost level of rules.
So the hundred meters and
the two hundred meters
which are the inner most
columns are dragged down
and if there's 100 or 200
meter that corresponds to
each male or female athlete
then this is listed.
To help you remember the stack function,
I try and visualize whether I want to make
this data frame taller or wider.
If I want to make the data frames taller,
then I need to use the stack function
because stacking gives
you a taller data frame.
Let's head over to the Jupiter
notebook to look at stacking.
Now remember that our original
data frame is called DF
and if we then us the stack function
we are going to end up with the
taller or longer data frame.
So df.stack
and we can see that the
corresponding data frame
that's been generated is taller.
Now in the real world, I
prefer to actually specify
which column I'm going to be
using in the stacking function.
So I would normally say df.stack
and specify the event
and I'll get exactly the same data frame.
In the next video, we'll cover unstack.