- [Instructor] With unstack,
we return a series or a DataFrame.
Because the NAN values,
or the missing data values are displayed,
you have the option to fill
them with another value.
So, in the example of the Olympic data set
that we are working on, it
would make sense to have
every NAN value to be zero,
because that means that
there were no medals won for that event.
With unstacking, you can pivot
a level of the index labels,
and this returns a DataFrame
having a new level of column labels.
If the index isn't a MultiIndex,
the output will be a series,
and the level involved will
automatically get sorted.
Let's head over to our Jupyter Notebook
to look at unstacking.
So, remember that our
original DataFrame is df,
and, when we do an unstack,
what we're looking at
is to try and get a wider DataFrame.
So, if i do a df.unstack,
I expect this original
DataFrame, df, to widen out.
And, as with stacking, I
prefer to explicitly state
which column I'm doing the unstacking on.
In this case, it's Gender.
So, I type df.unstack,
and enter the column name,
or the series name, Gender.
And, you can see that we end up in
exactly the same result as earlier.
And, in the next video, we will look at
a couple of challenge questions together.