- [Instructor] I'm really looking forward
to the challenges in this video.
I've got a fun couple of questions,
and this is a good opportunity
to practice combining stack and unstack,
groupby, and plotting.
These should take you
between five and 10 minutes,
so let's have a look at the questions.
Plot the number of gold
medals won by the USA male
and female athletes throughout
the history of the Olympics.
And finally, plot the five athletes
who have won the most gold medals
over the history of the Olympics.
When there is a tie, consider
the number of silver medals
and then bronze medals.
In the next video, I will work through
these solutions with you.