- [Instructor] Okay, so let's get started
on the stack and unstack
challenge questions
and remember that this is just
the way I'm going to solve them.
There are multiple ways
of solving these problems.
So, let's import pandas as pd.
Root in the data into our data frame.
Now, we want to plot the
number of gold medals
won by USA male and female athletes
throughout the history of the Olympics.
So, the first thing we want to do
is to determine which
athletes are from the USA
so, oo.NOC
equals USA
and because we're going to
have more than one condition
we include the conditions in parentheses
and we want the athletes
that have won a gold medal
so, oo.Medal equals Gold.
And let's store that in
the data frame gu for gold.
And let's confirm that this data frame
has the information we want.
So, the athletes are all from the USA,
we can see that in terms of gender
there's both male and female athletes.
All of them have won gold medals
and so we're good to go.
Now the next thing is
because we are looking for
athletes across the
history of the Olympics
we will want to group by
the edition and the gender.
So, let's group by edition
and gender.
And we can see here, that we've got male
and female athletes who have won medals
across the different editions.
So, we're getting closer
to the solution we want.
Now, in order to be able to plot this,
let's use the unstack command
so that we have the males
and female athlete medals in a data frame.
So, I'm going to do unstack.
And I'm going to specify that
I want to unstack by gender.
Now, what I want to do is
I want to get rid of the rows
where we have NaN or data values
because sometimes that causes
problems when using a plot.
So, I'm going to say,
fill value equals zero.
Right now we're in a position to plot.
So, I'm going to say, plot
and before I say plot I remember
that I haven't actually
imported the matplotlib library.
If I do a plot, I will end
up with this statement,
but clearly I need to be able
to plot it in my Jupyter notebook.
So, let me add my matplotlib
library here, so matplotlib.
As pot and I want to be
able to plot in line.
So, I go back to the statement
and I have a plot to cross
the different editions
for male and female US athletes
across the history of the Olympics.
Let's head over to the next question.
So, plot the five athletes
who have won the most gold medals
over the history of the Olympics.
When there is a tie, consider
the number of silver medals,
and then bronze medals.
So, again we are going to want to group
by the athletes and the medals.
So, oo, which is the
name of my data frame,
group by,
Athlete,
and Medals.
And I can see that I've
got the different athletes
and the number of medals that they've won.
Now, I want to be able
to do an unstack command
to separate out the number
of gold, silver and bronze medals.
So, I do an unstack
and I want to unstack my medal.
And our fill value equals zero.
Now, I've got the athletes
and the number of medals
that they have won.
The challenge that I have here is that
this is not sorted in any way.
So, if I want to determine
the five athletes
who've won the most number of gold medals,
I need to be able to sort this data frame.
So, let's store this data frame
and we'll call the data frame name g
and let's just make sure that
there's no problems there
and now I'm going to sort by
gold, silver, and bronze medals.
So, data frame g, sort values
by athletes who've won gold,
and then silver,
and then bronze.
And I can see that this is done
exactly what I've requested,
but I actually want to
sort the number of medals,
not in ascending order,
but in descending order.
So, I'm going to change
the ascending flag to false
and here I can see that this is sorting by
the number of gold medals first,
then silver, and then bronze.
Now, what would help is that
if I actually have this
data frame in that order.
So, gold, silver, and bronze.
So, let me change that
by including those series in a list.
So, gold, silver,
and then bronze.
And this is exactly
what I was looking for.
Now, what we want is
the top five athletes.
So, I can very easily
get the top five athletes
by just doing a head
and then if I want to plot that,
I plot that using a bar graph.
And so I see that the athlete
with the most number of
golds was Michael Phelps
followed by the other athletes
and then ending with Mark
Spitz and Carl Lewis.
So, you can see that when we use
stack, unstack, and group by in tandem,
we can do some pretty cool analysis.
In the next video,
we will look at some more
advanced data visualizations.