- [Instructor] In this video
we will install Continuum's Anaconda.
So, why Anaconda?
Anaconda comes with a lot of packages
that you need for data science.
We will also use Conda, a package manager.
Anaconda simplifies many of the challenges
that a lot of people who are not
full-time software
developers might run into.
These are things like installing
different versions of Python,
not having correct privileges,
or not having the required packages.
If you currently already have a version of
pip or Conda installed,
then you don't need to
reinstall everything.
Just check that you have the five packages
that we'll be using for
the course installed.
These are NumPy, pandas, matplotlib,
Seaborn, and Jupyter.
If you have pip, type pip
install and the package name,
so for example pip install
pandas for the pandas package.
If you have Conda, type Conda
install and the package name.
So, Conda install matplotlib
for the matplotlib package.
We will use Python 3.6.
Let's say you already have
another version of Python,
say 2.7, and you are already working
with some other packages there.
Then you might want to create a separate
virtual environment for this course.
To complete a brand new
installation of Anaconda,
head over to www.cotinuum.io/downloads.
Click on the Windows icon
and select Python 3.6 version 64-bit.
We don't want to install anything else.
Right, once we've downloaded
that, go to Show in Folder.
Select Run,
select Next,
review the license
agreement, click I Agree,
select Just Me.
Make sure that this destination folder
has no spaces in the destination path,
and I'm going to add Anaconda
to my path environment variable,
and select Install.
Once this has been completed, select Next,
and select Finish.
So, type Anaconda,
select the Anaconda Navigator here,
and don't show again, so
select OK and don't show again,
and you are now ready to go.
If you've run into any
problems during installation,
Continuum recommends temporarily disabling
your antivirus software
during installation,
then re-enabling it after
the installation concludes.
If you have installed for all users,
uninstall Anaconda and
reinstall it for your user only,
and try again.
In the next video we will
download our data set.