- [Instructor] In this video,
we will download our dataset
and store it in a folder
for us to access and use.
So let's get started by
downloading our dataset.
Do a search for Summer Olympic medal data.
Let's select the first link.
Select Get the data.
And select this link,
download the full spreadsheet.
We can download the data
as a Google Document.
The first tab, Forms Response 2,
doesn't seem to have
any information for us.
Neither does the second
tab, Form Responses 2.
If you go to the third tab,
we have a list of the medalists
at the Olympics per edition,
sport, discipline, gender, and event.
So the Breakdown shows the distribution
of gold, silver, and
bronze over the years.
The IOC Country Code helps
us to map the country codes
that we saw in the medalists'
names with the Country tab.
So the All Medalists tab seems
to have the most useful
information for us,
so let's download this as a CSV document.
The current name is a little long,
so I'm going to rename
that to just olympics.
And I'm going to store it
in a folder called data.
We will be using this dataset
for the entire course,
so make sure that you have it.
In the next video, we will
have a quick introduction
to Jupyter Notebooks.