- [Instructor] In this video,
we will get a better understanding
of using Jupyter notebooks.
Jupyter notebooks allow you to create
and share documents that have
live code, explanatory text,
equations, and visualizations.
There are two ways of doing this.
If you use Windows 10,
you can just look for
the Anaconda Navigator,
and launch Jupyter notebook
from there.
Alternatively, you can
go to the command prompt
by typing cmd, and then once
within the command prompt,
type jupyter notebook and hit Enter,
and this will retrieve
exactly the same thing.
This will open the Jupyter
notebook application
in the web browser on
the following address,
http localhost, and you can
see you've got 8890/tree.
The Files tab gives you
a list of all the files
in your current folder or directory.
The Running tab let's you
track your running processes
and any open Jupyter notebooks,
and the Clusters tab is now
provided by iPython parallel,
which is a Python package
and collection of CLI scripts
for controlling clusters for Jupyter.
To start a notebook, select
New under the File tab.
Select Python 3.
You can see there the notebook
name, a menu bar, a toolbar,
and an empty code cell.
There are two modes that
we're interested in using.
The first is to enter any text.
We enter this in the Code cells.
This is some text.
This is done in Markdown
in Jupyter notebooks.
The second mode allows
us to input and run code
within our notebook.
You can always select Markdown
or Code in the menu above
after selecting a code cell
by either using your
mouse or the up down arrow
on your keyboard.
Alternatively, you can
use keyboard shortcuts.
For example, if I hit Esc + M,
this means that the cell is now Markdown.
Now to evaluate or run this
cell, I hit Shift + Enter,
and you can see that I received
the text, this is some text.
Hitting Esc + Y means that
the cell is now in Code mode.
So for example if I type
32*32 and evaluate that
by hitting Shift + Enter,
that evaluates that cell.
There are only two other
commands that we need to learn.
If you want to learn
anymore keyboard shortcuts,
select Help, and Keyboard
shortcuts from the menu.
So Esc + V will insert empty code cells
below your current cell,
and Esc + A will insert
empty code cells above your current cell.
You can save this notebook
and give it a name.
In practice, what you might want to do is
share the notebook with other people.
Now that you know how
to create a notebook,
for the rest of this course
we will use the notebooks
that I have shared and
made available to you.
A tip for the real world.
It is important that you
maintain these notebooks.
These will be living
documents that you will share
with your data science colleagues.
You can build up a
portfolio that you can use
as a living resume to share
with perspective employers.
In many instances, if
you have used a notebook
and documented assumptions and steps,
if you come back to that
dataset at a later date,
it can save you a lot of time.
How useful your Jupyter
notebook will be to you
will be determined by how
well you document your work.
In the next video, we
will look at using Pandas.