- [Instructor] Now, in
order for us to use pandas,
we need to import Python's pandas library.
There are two ways of doing this.
We can type import pandas
and what this is doing is
importing Python's pandas library.
We're then in the position
to use the functions
available in this library.
And to use the functions,
we will type pandas dot
and the function name.
The other way to do is to
type import pandas as pd.
Here we are also importing
the Python's pandas library,
but we're using the alias pd.
This means that if you want
to access the functions
and methods available,
you only have to type pd
and the function name.
Pandas documentation is readily available.
All you need to do is
type a pd and the dot
and then hit the Tab key
and it will give you the options available
within that method.
PD? provides the doc string
or a summary of an
object and how to use it.
So, let's head over to
the Jupyter Notebook
to look at how we import pandas
and review the pandas documentation.
So, we can import pandas
by typing import pandas
and run that cell by
typing Shift and Enter.
And then if you want to
access any of the methods
so for example if we wanted
to know the versions of pandas
so pandas.show_versions,
this shows me not only
the version of pandas,
but it shows me the versions
of the dependencies for pandas.
I might want to shorten that
to just get the version for pandas
so I'll just type pandas two
underscores version underscore
and you can see that I'm
using pandas version 0.20.1.
Now, the other way to do
this is to use the alias
so I do import pandas as pd, run that,
and I can type pd version and run
and I get exactly the same output.
Now, on to pandas documentation.
I can type pd and then
I just need to hit Tab
and this gives me all
of the methods available
within the pandas library.
So, for example, when I used pd.show,
I can hit Tab here
and that will auto complete
that command for me.
If I want to get more
information about a doc string,
I can do a pd.show_versions
and a question mark
and this gives me information
about that package.
In this instance, there
isn't any doc string
for show version.
Let's try another method, pd.read_csv,
and here you can see I get
the doc string for read csv
which is read csv file into a dataframe.
In the next video,
we will look at series and dataframes
which are the building blocks of pandas.