- [Narrator] Data input and validation.
In this video, we will
cover how to read data
into a Pandas DataFrame
and validate the input.
You can read data stored in
a wide variety of formats,
such as excel, json, or SQL
database tables, amongst others.
Since our file is a CSV
file, we will use read_csv
which will allow us to read a comma
separated file into a DataFrame.
Read_csv has numerous parameters
and is very feature-rich.
You can specify a wide variety of options
including what column
headings to use for series,
additional delimeters for files, and ways
to parse any data fields.
We could easily spend
30 minutes just looking
at the different parameter
options for read_csv.
For now, we will only focus on
just a couple of the parameters.
The required parameter to read_csv
is the path to the CSV file.
The skiprows parameter allows
you to do exactly that.
If the first few lines do
not hold any relevant data,
then skip them.
We will now head over
to our Jupyter Notebook
to work through this.
The first thing we'll want
to do is to import Pandas.
We now need to specify the
name for our DataFrame.
I'm going to use oo = pd.read_csv
and I can hit Tab and this
will give me the options
of all of the different types
of formats that I can read in.
Since we're using a CSV
file, I'll select read_csv.
And this is a very helpful tip.
If my cursor is in between those brackets,
I can just hit Shift and Tab, and this
will provide me documentation.
If I hit Shift and Tab
again, I will get further
documentation, and then
I can hit Shift and Tab
three times, and that
will provide me all of the
options available within the read_csv file
or any method within Pandas.
I now need to specify the
path to that CSV file.
Since I know that the name
of my file is olympics,
I can just type O and hit Tab, and it
auto completes that for me.
I run the cell and now I want to look at
the results stored in that DataFrame.
We seem to have a problem here.
The first couple of rows
don't seem to make sense.
This is not what we want, so
let's head back to our CSV file
to try and understand why
this might be the case.
If we head back to the
CSV file, you can see that
we don't want to read the first couple
of rows into our DataFrame.
The table of information that we want
really starts from here, so we want to
skip those first four rows and
read from row five onwards.
So we'll head back to our DataFrame.
We can provide the parameter, skiprows=4.
We now see that this is what we would
expect to see in our DataFrame.
This starts at the start of
the table of the CSV file
so the first athlete is HAJOS, Alfred.
We go back to that, and we
see row six, HAJOS, Alfred
and we know that we are good to go.
In the next video, we will
look at the shape attribute.