- [Instructor] Shape.
The shape attribute returns a tuple,
that's rows and columns representing
the dimensionality of the DataFrame.
It's a good idea to check this
against the original CSV file
to ensure that all the expected data
has been read into the DataFrame.
The shape attribute is useful
for confirming the dimensions
of your dataset.
We'll head over to our Jupyter Notebook.
What we need to enter
here is our DataFrame
which is 00 and shape,
the shape attribute.
So, the 29,216 corresponds
to the number of rows
in the CSV file
and the 10 corresponds
to the number of columns.
We can confirm that
and we can see for example here
that the city, edition, sport and so on,
these are the 10 columns that we have
and we actually have 29,216
rows of data in our table.
One helpful tip is that sometimes
you might only want the number of rows
or columns as part of your code
and you can extract this information
from this tuple by just typing shape
and zero for the number of rows
and if you just want the column,
you can enter the one there
providing you that second
component of your tuple
which are the 10 columns
that you have in the data.
In the next video
we will look at head and tail.