- [Instructor] The head and
the tail return the first
and last N rows of a DataFrame.
This is one of the first steps
after reading a file
into a Pandas DataFrame
just to get a feel of the
rows and columns involved.
By default you will
get the first five rows
and the last five rows
if you don't specify any value of N.
Let's head over to our Jupyter Notebook.
So, we enter our DataFrame
which is 00 and head.
And that gives us the first five rows
of our DataFrame.
Alternatively, if we
want the last five rows,
we enter 0.tail and that
gives us the last five rows
and so, we can see that the first five,
the data seems to be
sorted by the edition,
the first five are the ones
for the first Olympics
and the last five are from the information
that we have on the last
Olympics from the 2008.
A helpful tip is that sometimes
if you sorted your DataFrame or series,
you might only want to
display the top three results.
You can do that by typing 00.head
and three and that will give you
the top three rows.
Another example of where
you might want to use
the head method is when you've just read
in a CSV file into your DataFrame
and then you want to view it.
So, an example of where the
head is very helpful is here.
I would normally run head
straight after reading
the CSV file into the DataFrame.
Here I can check very quickly
that the DataFrame is in the format
that I would expect.
In the next video we will look at info
which provides a summary of a DataFrame.