- [Instructor] Info provides
a summary of the data frame
including the number of
entries, the data type,
and the number of non-null entries
for each series in the data frame.
This is important because
often when working
with a real data set,
there will be missing data.
You want a view of this to determine
how you will handle this missing data.
Let's head back to the Jupyter notebook.
So I enter the name of the data frame.
We can see that we do not have
any missing data in this data set.
There are 29,216 entries,
and none of them are non-null.
What is also useful about the info method
is that it also gives you the data types
for the different series of columns.
This is useful when you have to do
any comparisons or queries.
So for example, if you are
querying what is a string,
then you will know that
you have to use quotes,
and if you are using a
comparison for an integer
or a float value, then you
won't need to use those quotes.
In the next video, we will
learn how to use Pandas
to do some basic data analysis.