(swooshing cymbals)
- [Instructor] So this is
an interesting question
that has a lot of moving parts.
I'm going to show you one
of the ways to solve it.
In every Olympics,
which US athlete has won
the most total number of medals?
Include the athlete's discipline.
So, again, we're interested in
only the athletes from the USA
so we use our dataframe and
we say, oo.NOC equals USA,
and let's store that in the variable,
which is our dataframe, gy.
Now, given that we want
to determine the values
for every Olympics, we
will need to group by
the Edition, the Athlete, the Medal.
So, if I do a groupby on the gy dataframe
on the Edition, the
Athlete, and the Medal,
and I do a sizeof there,
I can see that I've got
the Edition, the Athlete, and the Medals.
So, I want to do an unstack,
and the reason I want to
do an unstack is because,
then, I'm in a position to
have three different columns,
Silver, Gold, and Bronze,
and then I can add those three columns
to get the total number of medals.
So, I do an unstack of the Medal.
I'll do a fill_value
equal zero, and run that.
Now, what I'm going to do is to create
a new column called
Total, so I'm going to say
the total number of medals here
is the total number of Gold,
add the total number of Silver medals,
and add the total number of Bronze medals.
And, let's just confirm
our new data frame.
It looks like we've run into an error.
And, there seems to be a problem
with the KeyError: 'Gold'.
If we go back to this, we
need to assign the groupby
to the dataframe gy, and
then we should be good to go.
And so, we can see here
that we've got a new series
called Total in our dataframe,
which is the sum of the Bronze,
the Gold, and the Silver.
Now, what we want to be able to do here
is to go through each
Edition and determine
who is the US athlete who's
won the most number of medals.
And, we do that by sorting
each of these groups.
So, what I'm going to do is is
I'm going to reset my index.
So, we're now going to
just work our way through
each of those groups created
by the groupby object.
So, for year and group
in gy, groupby Edition,
I'm just going to print out what
I'm going to get for each group.
And, you see that for each Edition,
I'm getting the total number
of medals for that group.
Now, I want to be able to sort this group.
So, when I refer to a
group, I'm referring to
all of the medals won for that Edition,
and I want to be able to sort those values
by the total number of
medals won for that Edition.
And, more specifically, I'm
interested in the athlete
who has won the most number of medals.
So, I do a group, sort values,
and I want to sort values
by the total number of medals won.
And, remember, because I'm
looking for the athlete
who has won the most medals,
I want the ascending flag to be false.
Now, because I'm looking
for the athlete who has won
the most medals for each Edition,
I just want the top-most entry here.
So, I enter a colon and a
one, and that will give me
just the top-most entry for each Edition.
And, I've got the information that I want.
Now, the easiest way to deal with this
is to store all of this in a list.
So, let me just take all of this,
and store it in a list
using Python's list command.
So, for year, groupby Edition,
and let's store all of the
information that we get
as a result of this in the list,
and let's call that top
USA, so tu for top USA.
And, let's view that list, tu.
The reason that we are storing
all of the information in a
list is so that we can then
populate the dataframe from
the elements in the list.
So, I'm going to create a
new dataframe called top.
I'll say pd.DataFrame,
and now I'm going to work
my way through the list,
so for every element, i, in the list, tu,
top, which is my dataframe, is
going to append that element
to the dataframe.
If I then enter top,
which is the new dataframe
I've created, I'm going to
append each element of the list,
and each element is the element i.
And so, if I then run this command,
I should then get the dataframe.
And, in that dataframe is the
top element for that group.
And so, we can see that for 1896
the US athlete who has won
the most total number of
medals is Robert Garrett.
And, if we work our way
down, there you have it.
Michael Phelps was the most
successful athlete in 2008,
and you've used Python's
Pandas to prove it.