- [Instructor] Indexing.
The index object is an immutable array,
and indexing allows you to access
a row or a column using a label.
This is what makes Pandas special,
because typically in other
programming languages,
you cannot access an array using labels.
Let's head over to the Jupyter notebook
to look at a couple of examples.
So let's import Pandas's
PD and let's import
our CSV dataset into our dataframe oo.
To try and understand a
little bit more about indexes,
let's look at their type, and you can see
that an index has its own type
and is not series or a dataframe.
Let's look at the hundredth
element for this dataframe.
So oo, index, and 100,
and we can see that it's returned
the number 100 because
that's the hundredth element
or the hundredth element
in that dataframe.
Now indexes are immutable,
so that means we cannot change them.
So oo.index, and if I try and change 100
to become, say, five, I get an error.
I get an "Index does not support
mutable operations" error.
In this video, we covered the
basic properties of the index,
but there's a lot more to indexes.
We will cover these in
the next couple of videos.