- [Narrator] The set index allows us
to determine which of the
series is going to be the index.
We will use the set index
with one key parameter, which is the keys.
We will look at inplace in particular,
in the next Jupyter notebook.
Now remember that I said, one
of the advantages of Pandas
is that you can use labels as an index.
So let's set the athlete
series as our index.
Now, what I'm going to do is
I'm going to show you two
ways of going about this.
So let's look at our original
data frame, which is oo.head.
And we can see that currently,
the index is this first column.
And this data frame is
indexed by these numbers.
Now, if I want to set
the athlete as the index,
one way of doing this is
to use the oo.set index
and I specify that I want this data frame
indexed by athlete.
And you can see, that the
athlete is now in bold,
and this first column is your index.
Now, let's confirm that the
athlete is in fact our index.
So I'm going to do another
head on my original data frame,
and surprisingly, we
find that the data frame
has reverted to the original index.
There is a very simple reason for this.
And that is, that when we set index,
we need to set the index to athlete.
Now, what we need to do is we need
to specify that inplace is equal to true
so that those changes are made
to the original data frame.
If we then go and do a
head on this data frame,
we see that it has
maintained the athlete index
and we can now proceed and
search by the athlete name.
Now, I'm going to show you another way
of going about setting an index,
but before I do that, I'm
going to just reset this index.
Don't worry about this line right yet,
I'll walk through it in the next video.
So, again, I use the data
frame, I say set index
and my index is going to be athlete.
Now, I know that if I do this,
this is not going to work
because in place equals false,
so what I can do is I can make
a copy of this data frame,
and store it in the data
frame ath for athlete.
And then, when I look at
the first couple of rows
for the athlete data frame, I see
that this has been indexed by athlete.
In the next video, we
will look at reset index.