- [Narrator] Now, not surprisingly,
the opposite of setting an
index is to reset the index.
And what we're doing here is
we're returning a DataFrame
to its default, integer-based index.
Let's head over to our Jupyter
notebook for an example.
Now we know that ath is a data frame
that is indexed by athlete,
because we did this in the previous video.
So let's reset the ath data frame,
so that it is indexed by the integers.
So ath.reset_index,
and SHIFT and TAB to look
at the options, and we see
that we run into the same problem
that we did with set_index
where we need to specify
that the inplace is true, if we want
to do it to the ath data frame,
or we can specify that
inplace equals false,
and then we need to set this data frame
to another data frame.
So let's say, inplace equals true.
And we do an ath.head and
here we expect the index
to be back to the integer-based
indices for our data frame.
In the real world, you can
often use the reset index,
especially when you're trying to determine
which is the best series to use
as an index for your data frame.
In the next video, we will
look at sorting an index.