- [Instructor] Now I want to sort index.
Sort index allows for all
the items to be sorted
by that index.
The advantage of this is that
when you have a particularly
large data set, sorting
the index reduces the time
to access any subset of that data.
You can sort objects by
a label along the axis.
Let's head over to the Jupyter Notebook
to look at a couple of examples.
Let's reuse the ATH data frame
that we created in the previous video.
So ath.head gives us the
first couple of rows.
Now let's set the index
to the athlete name,
so ath.set index to athlete.
And we'll do that in place.
So if we're now doing ath.head,
and now we can see that the
index is by the athlete's name.
So let's now sort that index.
So ath.sort index,
and we specify that that's
looking at in place equals true.
So we want to change that
in place equals false
to in place equals true.
And let's see what changes
we see to the ATH data frame.
And we can see that the
athlete is now the index
for the data frame.
And this has now been
sorted by athlete name.
And so the first five
rows have now changed
from Alfred and Otto to Aabye and Aaltonen
because these are sorted alphabetically.
Now, let's say we wanted
to sort the index,
so that it was in descending
alphabetical order.
We can change the flag ascending to false.
And we can see that there's been a change
in the index for the athletes' names
as they are now sorted in reverse order.
You might have been surprised to see
that the O with the umlauts are at the end
rather than a name starting with zed or Z.
This is because with this encoding,
the standard alphabet
will have a lower value
than the special characters
used in other languages.
So if your data has special characters,
you need to take this into account.
In the next videos, we
will look at loc and iloc.