- [Announcer] "loc[]" is
a label-based indexer,
that means you are
selecting by the labels.
And notice that "loc[]"
uses square brackets
and not regular brackets.
"loc[]" will raise the KeyError
when items are not found.
Let's head over to the jupyter
Notebook to look at a couple
of examples.
If I wanted to search the Olympic table
by the athlete's names,
I could try for example, "oo.",
which is the name of my data frame,
"loc" and if I look for Usain Bolt,
I end up with a KeyError saying
"The label [BOLT, USAIN]
Is not in the ".
Why might this be the case?
If I look at my data frame again,
I can see that the index
is not the athlete's name,
but is the integer based index.
So what I can do is I can set the index
to the athlete's name,
set inplace to true
and try again.
Bolt, Usain.
And you can see now that
I get a list of rows
of all of the medals
that Usain Bolt has won
in the Olympics.
Now, you might think that
the only way to access
Usain Bolt's entry is if we
set the index to athlete,
but we can actually use a
more traditional approach
that we've seen before.
I'm going to first reset the index.
And if I wanted to get any
information on Usain Bolt,
so, let's just check that
the data frame is in the
format that we expect
traditionally, we would have
accessed Usain Bolt's entry
using his name in this way, so,
oo.Athlete == 'BOLT, Usain'
I can use loc here, so,
dataframe oo.loc to
give me the same result.
In the next video, we will look at ILook.