- [Instructor] Here with Iloc,
we're doing selection by integer index.
Iloc is primarily integer position based.
One of the advantages of Iloc
is that it allows for the
traditional Pythonic slicing.
Let's take a look at a couple of examples
in the jupyter notebook.
Let's review our data frame again.
If I want to see the 1,700th entry,
or the index entry,
I would type oo.iloc,
and remember it's square brackets, 1700.
I can see that this
corresponds to the athlete,
Pierre Rabot.
What I can also do with Iloc,
is to use a list.
So, oo. for my data frame, iloc,
and then a list of integers.
For example, I might want the
integer index 1542, 2390,
6000, and 15000.
This will return the rows
corresponding to these index.
I mentioned earlier that Iloc allows for
the traditional Pythonic slicing,
so, for example, if I do an oo.head,
and look at the first five
entries in my data frame,
if I wanted to only see
the entries one to three,
I could use Pythonic
slicing and do a oo.iloc.1:4
and these will return the
indexes with one, two, and three.
Loc and Iloc can be used
for different things.
In the real world, I would often
use one of the other series
as my index, and so,
I would typically use Loc for indexing.
However, if my data is
sorted in a way that allows
me to use the default index,
then I might use Iloc,
especially when I want
to access chunks of data
using Python slicing.
In the next video,
we will look at a couple
of challenge questions.